Carolina Carneiro

Berlin, Berlin, Germany

carneiro.carolina@yahoo.com.br

linkedin.com/in/carolina-santos-carneiro

Summary

I'm a since 2018 Berlin-based ex-German teacher who got to participate on a Hackathon to develop an app to teach German and ended up finding more interesting the programming part than the German language one. Since then, my tech journey started and now I've been on it for more than 3 years.

I love to develop interesting applications, to show my creativity through coding and to see the very nice results development technologies allow us to have.

In my Software Engineering path, I made experiences with:

Data Science and Machine Learning

Python

Java

HTML, CSS, Javascript (WebDev core combo)

©##

♀# Agile methods and SCRUM frameworks

Personally, I'm also:
Part of the LGBTQIA+ community
Into MMROPG
Very much into music making and producing
Amateur bike lover
Q# Feminist (intersectional)

Please, if you think my profile is interesting do not hesitate to connect or to send me a message:)

Experience

itacs Software Development Apprenticeship

itacs

Mar 2022 - Present (6 months +)

Self Employed Translator and Language Instructor

Autônomo

Jul 2015 - Present (7 years 2 months +)

Tutoring and Translations for German students with very positive feedback from them.

Working Student Business Analytics (FR/IT)

Audible

Oct 2019 - Feb 2020 (5 months)

Education



ReDI School of Digital Integration

Python Fundamentals, Computer Programming

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

Fundamentals of coding, such as coding structures and logic using Python.

Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Computer Science and German Linguistics

2020 - 2021

Exchange semesters in the fields of Computer Science and Linguistics



SPICED Academy

Data Science Bootcamp, Date Science

2019 - 2019

Data Analysis in Python

Machine learning

Data visualization and reporting

SQL & NoSQL

Data Infrastructures

Git & Github



Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro

Bachelor Degree in International Relations and Affairs, International Relations and **Affairs**

2012 - 2016

Colégio Farroupilha

High School

2002 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications



Goethe Certificate C1 - Goethe-Institut e.V.



Sololearn Completion Python 3 Tutorial - Sololearn

Certificate #1073-13212859



DSH Certificate C2 - Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin



Goethe Zertifikat C2 - Goethe-Institut e.V.

- Learn C# Course Codecademy
- Learn JavaScript Course Codecademy
- ReDI

Coding Fundamentals - ReDI School of Digital Integration

Skills

C# • .NET-Framework • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Microsoft Office • Negotiation • Team Leadership • Teamwork • Spanish

Honors & Awards

German Reading Contest - Coordination of German Language in the States of Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina

Apr 2008

1st place in the category German as a Foreign Language

German State Reading Contest - Coordination of German Language in the States of Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina

May 2008

3rd place in the German as a Foreign Language category

German Language Reading Contest - Coordination of German Language in the States of Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina

May 2011

1st place in the German as a Second Language Category

Machine Learning Hackathon Servus Alexa - N3XTCODER

Jan 2019

The mission for the Hackathon:

Draw on a worldwide network of german learners to create the largest database of accents for machine learning available

Gamify the creation of the largest training set for accent recognition available to machine learning Develop with us a new Al to help non-German speakers to learn german

Build the new generation of Virtual Assistants for language learning